<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Lotus Buddhism</title>
    <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Lotus Buddhism</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Altruism</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/altruism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/altruism/</guid>
      <description>Altruism is the most effective means of self-realization and self-perfection. Doing good for others is the best way to develop one’s own character and find greater happiness for oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attitude</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/attitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/attitude/</guid>
      <description>No matter what the problem is, the way it is interpreted can have a positive or negative effect on one&amp;rsquo;s life. By adopting a positive interpretation, one can make one’s problems a source of nourishment for personal growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodhisattva is a World Citizen</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/bodhisattva-is-a-world-citizen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/bodhisattva-is-a-world-citizen/</guid>
      <description>You must not yoke yourself to nationality or to ethnicity. You are more than just your physical being. Do not regard yourself as a slave to your genes. Fundamentally, all human beings have limitless and immense potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desires</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/desires/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/desires/</guid>
      <description>We could not live without desires. Often, desires generate the energy that enables us to move forward and improve ourselves. The key question, therefore, is how we use desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determine to win</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/determine-to-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/determine-to-win/</guid>
      <description>We are not defeated by adversity but by the loss of the will to strive. However devastated you may feel, so long as you have the will to fight on, you can surely triumph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearlessness</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/fearlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/fearlessness/</guid>
      <description>Chanting is the way to destroy all fear. It is the way to banish sorrow, the way to light a torch of hope. It is the revolution that rewrites the scenario of our destiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hope</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/hope/</guid>
      <description>As long as one has hope, there is nothing one cannot achieve; everything is born from hope. Our life force, our fundamental energy, is fueled by hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inner Resolve</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/inner-resolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/inner-resolve/</guid>
      <description>To resolve to accomplish your goals is what counts. If you earnestly put your mind to something, your brain, your body, your environment – everything – will start working toward achieving that end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep moving </title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/keep-moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/keep-moving/</guid>
      <description>The important thing is to start from where you can and give your all to challenging something new. Then, just like climbing a mountain, keep moving towards your goal, one step at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/love/</guid>
      <description>Ideal love is fostered only between two sincere, mature and independent people. Real love is not two people clinging to each other; it can only be fostered between two strong people secure in their individuality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a start</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/making-a-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/making-a-start/</guid>
      <description>Whatever your circumstances, whatever your past, the forces that determine your future are nowhere but within your own heart and mind. It is here that the star of your destiny shines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openness</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/openness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/openness/</guid>
      <description>Make an effort to meet with people. Interaction with others opens up new and exciting possibilities. Meeting people stimulates our minds, gives us energy, leads to more new encounters and infinitely expands our life and our world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/purpose/</guid>
      <description>Everyone born in this world has a unique role that only he or she can fulfill. Were this not the case, we would not be here. The universe never acts without cause; everything invariably has a reason for being. Even the weeds people love to loathe serve a purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/relationships/</guid>
      <description>If you want to change another person, first change your own heart. When you change, others around you will change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise to the challenges</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/rise-to-the-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/rise-to-the-challenges/</guid>
      <description>Rise to the challenge of life&amp;rsquo;s trials and tribulations. You can&amp;rsquo;t develop genuine character and ability by sidestepping adversity and struggle. Work hard. Sometimes others may taunt you or try to deter you, but just keep pressing forwards and win. All of this is training in life, and all of it becomes your treasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting goals</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/setting-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/setting-goals/</guid>
      <description>Life moves toward the direction our mind aims it in. A goal activates our minds and bodies; it stimulates wisdom and energy from within.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing strength</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/your-unique-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/your-unique-story/</guid>
      <description>When we care for others our own strength to live increases. When we help people expand their state of life, our lives also expand. Actions to benefit others are not separate from actions to benefit oneself. Our lives and the lives of others are ultimately inseparable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‏Starting afresh</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/starting-afresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/starting-afresh/</guid>
      <description>The worst mistake you can make is to give up on yourself and stop challenging yourself for fear of failure. Keep moving forward with a firm eye on the future, telling yourself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll start from today!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll start afresh from now, from this very moment!&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step by step</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>A pyramid isn’t built from the top down. The apex is attained only by laying strong foundation stones, one by one. The same is true of achieving a lofty objective. T he crucial thing is to lay the first stone, to take the first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The present moment</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/the-present-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/the-present-moment/</guid>
      <description>Even a cave that has been in total darkness for millions of years will become brightly illuminated the moment a light is brought inside. It is always the present that counts.
It is what we do in the present moment that decides our future.
Our past causes do not govern our future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/transformation/</guid>
      <description>Transform sadness into courage. Transform karma into a mission. Break through the darkness and make the morning sun rise in your hearts. Come, dancing forth like a reborn sun heralding the arrival of spring</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniqueness</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/uniqueness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/uniqueness/</guid>
      <description>Just as cherry, plum, peach and damson blossoms all possess their own unique qualities, each person is unique. We cannot become someone else. The important thing is that we live true to ourselves and cause the great flower of our lives to blossom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Goodness?</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/what-is-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/what-is-goodness/</guid>
      <description>“Goodness” can be defined as that which moves us in the direction of harmonious coexistence, empathy and solidarity with others. The nature of evil, on the other hand, is to divide: people from people, humanity from the rest of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wholeheartedness</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/wholeheartedness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/wholeheartedness/</guid>
      <description>If you are half-hearted about your job, you can never put your full strength into your religious activities either.
Now is the time for you to clench your teeth and exert yourself both in your work and your faith, no matter how hard pressed you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working together</title>
      <link>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/sense-of-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lotusbuddhism.info/quote/sense-of-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Instead of one person taking one hundred steps forwards, let’s aim at one hundred people taking one step forwards! It’s when many capable people are awakened to their noble missions it is certain that they can each achieve fresh new victories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
